Guide to the Robert B. Fisher Photograph Collection and Papers WA MSS S-2823
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, 1842-1932; Series V; 1; 1 box
  - Subjects Not in the United States
    - United Kingdom
      - Lyte, H.C. Maxwell. "Eton College." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 53.316 (1876): 519-528., 1876 September (Box 25, Folder 1153)
      - Conway, Moncure Daniel. "South-coast Saunterings in England. The Isle of Wight. – II (Saunter V)" Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 40.238 (1870): 523-542., 1870 February-March (Box 25, Folder 1154)
      - O'Connor, V. C. Scott. "Tennyson and his Friends at Freshwater." The Century. 55.2 (1897): 240-267., 1897 December (Box 25, Folder 1155)
      - Sikes, Wirt. "On the Taff." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 54.321 (1877): 519-528., 1877 February (Box 25, Folder 1156)
      - Sikes, Wirt. "On the Welsh Border." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 56.332 (1878): 211-224., 1878 January (Box 25, Folder 1157)
  - Portraits
    - Engravings based on photographs and published in Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper. 3.68 and 3.77 (1857)., 1857 March 28, May 30 (Box 25, Folder 1158)
    - Johnson, Thomas, engraver. "Harriet Beecher Stowe" from a photograph by Napoleon Sarony and published in The Century. 34.6 (1887): frontispiece., 1887 October (Box 25, Folder 1159)
    - Johnson, Thomas, engraver. "John Ruskin" from a photograph by Herbert R. Barraud, circa 1882 (Box 25, Folder 1160)
    - Johnson, Thomas, engraver. "Washington Irving" from a photograph by John Plumbe, circa 1880; (2 copies) (Box 25, Folder 1161)
    - Kruell, Gustav, engraver. "Horace Greeley" from a photograph by Napoleon Sarony, circa 1873 (Box 25, Folder 1162)
    - McNeill, Ronald J. "Notable Women. Jenny Lind." The Century. 45.28 (1892): 207-210., 1892 December (Box 25, Folder 1163)
    - Stewart, George. "Alfred, Lord Tennyson." The Cosmopolitan, 14.2 (1892): 169-178., 1892 December (Box 25, Folder 1164)
    - "William Wood," based on a photograph by Kurtz, and "M. Hall Stanton," based on a photograph by Gutekunst, published in Harper's Weekly, 20.998 (1876): 124., 1876 February 12 (Box 25, Folder 1165)
  - Photography
    - Abbott, Austin. "The Eye and the Camera." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 39.232 (1869): 476-482., 1869 September; (2 copies) (Box 25, Folder 1166)
    - Bogardus, Abraham. "The Lost Art of the Daguerreotype." The Century. 68.1 (1904): 83-91., 1904 May (Box 25, Folder 1167)
    - Caffin, Charles H. "Photography as a Fine Art." Everybody's Magazine. 4.19 (1901): 195-203., 1901 March (Box 25, Folder 1168)
    - "Composite Portraits of Men of Genius." The Strand Magazine. 31.185 (1906): 523-528, 1906 June (Box 25, Folder 1169)
    - "Curious Optical Illusions (For the Children)." Demorest's Family Magazine., circa 1895 (Box 25, Folder 1170)
    - "Daguerre Tablet Starts French Debate: His Partner, Niepce, Now Given Part Credit for Inventing Photography." New York Times. (1925):, 1925 July 19 (Box 25, Folder 1171)
    - Davidson, Mary. "The Babies of Chinatown." Cosmopolitan. 28.6 (1900): 605-612., 1900 April (Box 25, Folder 1172)
    - Davis, D. T., Mrs. "The Daguerreotype in America." McClure's Magazine. 8.1 (1896): 3-16., 1896 November (Box 25, Folder 1173)
    - Eddy, William A. "A Camera in Mid-Air." St. Nicholas. 27 (1900): 725-728., 1900 June (Box 25, Folder 1174)
    - "Fairmount Water-Works." The Young People's Book. 2.12. (1842): 41-42., 1842 August (Box 25, Folder 1175)
    - Hewer, J. Martin. "Photographic Silhouettes: The Dark Side of Celebrities." The Strand Magazine. 39.230 (1910): 184-187., 1910 February (Box 25, Folder 1176)
    - "Hi-Art." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 14.81 (1857): 426., 1857 February (Box 25, Folder 1177)
    - Kearton, R. "Natural History Photography." Pearson's Magazine. 3.6 (1900): 500-506., 1900 June (Box 25, Folder 1178)
    - King, Pauline. "The Charming Daguerreotype." The Century Illustrated Monthly Magazine. 68.1 (1904): 81-82., 1904 May; (2 copies) (Box 25, Folder 1179)
    - Knight, Edward H. "Photo-Micrography." Harper's New Monthly Magazine. 50.298 (1875): 543., 1875 March (Box 25, Folder 1180)
    - Jackson, Sidney W. "With a Camera in the Bush." Pearson's Magazine. 6.5 (1901): 629-632., 1901 November (Box 25, Folder 1181)
    - "The Largest Photograph in the World." Collier's Weekly. 32 (1904): 11., 1904 January (Box 25, Folder 1182)
    - "A Living Picture of the Famous Liberty Bell." Bulletin of the Pan American Union. 47 (1918): 266., 1918 July-December; (2 copies) (Box 25, Folder 1183)
    - Moysey, G.E. "Silhouette Photography." The Strand Magazine. 28.165 (1904): 354-355., 1904 September (Box 25, Folder 1184)
    - "Photograph Collecting Fad.", circa 1890 (Box 25, Folder 1185)
      Photocopy from an unidentified newspaper
    - Price, Sara Delavergne. "How the Big Tree was Sent to Chicago." The American Magazine. 35.6 (1893): 728-734., 1893 June (Box 25, Folder 1186)
    - Tarbell, Ida M. "A Great Photographer." McClure's Magazine. 9.1 (1897): 559-564., 1897 May; (2 copies) (Box 25, Folder 1187)
    - "The Tragedies of a Camera." The Strand Magazine. 16.95 (1898): 545-552., 1898 November (Box 25, Folder 1188)
    - "The Travelling Photographer." The Illustrated London News. 63.1776 (1873): 237., 1873 September (Box 25, Folder 1189)
    - Ward, H. Snowden. "The Work of the Camera." The Sketch. (1894): 687-688., 1894 April 25
    - Woodrow, Wilson, Mrs. "The Fascination of Being Photographed and the Improvement in Photography." Cosmopolitan. 35 (1903): 675-684., 1903 October (Box 25, Folder 1190)
  - Gigantism
    - Dana, Charles L. "Giants and Giantism." Scribner's Magazine. 17.2 (1895): 179-185., 1895 February (Box 25, Folder 1191)
    - Linden, George. "Human Sky-Scrapers." The Scrap Book. 5.5 (1908): 769-775., 1908 May (Box 25, Folder 1192)
    - Smythies, W. Gordon. "Some Famous Giants." The English Illustrated Magazine. 16.162 (1897): 667-674., 1897 March (Box 25, Folder 1193)
- Papers, 1977-1998; Series VI; 3.1; 8 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  Computer disks are restricted. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Series VI is organized into four subseries: Writings, Correspondence, Photographic Collection Documentation, and Subject Files.
  This series consists of writings, correspondence, and subject files related chiefly to the photographic collection of Fisher and the history of photography.
  Individual titles and dates of articles and material in the subject files were not captured during processing the collection.
  - Writings
    - Fisher, Robert B. "The Hogg Connection." Daguerrian Annual (1990): 101-114. (Box 26, Folder 1194-1195)
    - "Hogg, Beard, Fardon (Work Copy), Fardon Ad Hoc Justice, final draft", 1992; (1 computer disk)
    - Fisher, Robert B. "The Beard Photographic Franchise in England." Daguerrian Annual (1992): 73-95. (Box 26, Folder 1196-1203)
    - "The Beard Photography Franchise in England", 1993 March; (1 computer disk)
    - Fisher, Robert B. "Ad Hoc Justice Documented: The 'Paper Daguerreotypes' of George Robinson Fardon." Journal of the West. 33.2 (1994): 6-12., 1994 April (Box 26, Folder 1204-1212)
  - Correspondence
    - Appollo, Ken, 1991-1996 (Box 26, Folder 1213)
    - Ball, Geoffrey, 1980-1982 (Box 26, Folder 1214)
    - Brindl Fine Arts, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 1215)
    - Brown, Gerald, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 1216)
    - The Daguerrian Society, 1991-1995 (Box 26, Folder 1217)
    - Hickman, Paul, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 1218)
    - Kailbourn, Thomas R., 1993 (Box 26, Folder 1219)
    - McManus, Howard R., 1991-1993 (Box 26, Folder 1220)
    - Palmquist, Peter, 1990-1998 (Box 26, Folder 1221)
    - Payton, Crystal, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 1222)
    - Russack, Richard, undated (Box 26, Folder 1223)
    - Smus, Louis H., undated (Box 26, Folder 1224)
    - Thayer, Christopher, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 1225)
    - Todd, Suzanne, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 1226)
    - Treadwell, T.K., 1991 (Box 26, Folder 1227)
    - Waters, Dennis, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 1228)
    - Wood, John, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 1229)
  - Photographic Collection Documentation
    Research compiled by Fisher about collecting photograph and documentation about his collection.
    - Collecting photographs (Box 27, Folder 1230-1235)
    - Collection inventories (Box 27, Folder 1236-1247)
    - Sales from the collection (Box 27, Folder 1248-1251)
  - Subject Files
    - California history
      - Facsimile reproduction of The Californian newspaper, March 15, 1848, published by Theron Fox, circa 1970
        The issue includes the first notice for the discovery of gold on the South Fork American River near a sawmill owned by Johann August Sutter (1803-1880), also known as Sutter's Mill
      - Todd, Suzanne. Hawley Family and Interrelated Families of Washington Township, 1993
        Family tree for the family of James Hawley (1822-1906) and Hettie Munn Hawley (1822-1911) of Washington Township, Alameda County, California.
    - Individual photographers
      - Beard, Richard (Box 28, Folder 1252-1255)
      - Clayton, James Atkins (Box 28, Folder 1256-1262)
      - Draper, John William (Box 28, Folder 1263-1265)
      - Fardon, George Robinson (Box 28, Folder 1266-1280)
      - Fenton, Roger (Box 28, Folder 1281-1303)
      - Hogg, Jabez (Box 29, Folder 1304-1322)
      - Langenheim, William, and Frederick Langenheim (Box 29, Folder 1323-1324)
      - Plumbe, John (Box 29, Folder 1325-1332)
    - Photographers by location
      - Photographers in the Middle East (Box 30, Folder 1333)
      - Photographers in the United Kingdom (Box 30, Folder 1334-1349)
      - Photographers in the United States (Box 31, Folder 1350-1355)
        - Daguerreotypes, early American (Box 31, Folder 1356-1377)
        - Early California Photographs (Box 31, Folder 1378-1385)
        - San Francisco Commercial Photography (Box 31, Folder 1386-1387)
        - Yosemite National Park (Box 31, Folder 1388-1392)
    - Photographic genres
      - Cartes de visite (Box 32, Folder 1393-1396)
      - Calotype and salted paper prints (Box 32, Folder 1397-1405)
      - Color photography (Box 32, Folder 1406-1416)
      - Daguerreotypes (Box 32, Folder 1417-1419)
      - Daguerreotype cases (Box 32, Folder 1420)
      - Lantern slides (Box 32, Folder 1421-1442)
      - Lantern slide advertising, 1890-1895
      - Moving pictures (Box 32, Folder 1443-1454)
      - Moving pictures, oversize, 1923-1925
      - Pannotypes (Box 32, Folder 1455-1458)
      - Photographic Books (Box 32, Folder 1459)
      - Photography equipment advertisements (Box 32, Folder 1460-1464)
      - Photography equipment advertisements, oversize, 1847-1890
      - Photomechanical processes (Box 32, Folder 1465-1486)
      - Stereographs (Box 32, Folder 1487-1505)
        - Daguerreotype stereographs (Box 32, Folder 1506-1512)
        - French stereographs (Box 32, Folder 1513-1516)
        - Glass stereographs (Box 32, Folder 1517-1533)
        - Stereograph catalogs (Box 32, Folder 1534-1539)
        - The Stereoscopic Magazine (Box 32, Folder 1540-1541)
        - Tissue stereographs (Box 32, Folder 1542-1543)
      - Tintypes (Box 32, Folder 1544)
    - Photographic organizations
      - Daguerrian Society (Box 33, Folder 1545-1549)
      - Magic Lantern Society (Box 33, Folder 1550)
    - Postmarks (Box 33, Folder 1551-1555)
    - Research Trips (Box 33, Folder 1556-1561)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 1992-1993; 0.2; 1 box
  - Computer disks, 1992, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 1562-1563)
- Oversize, 1847-1993; 0.1; 1 box + 1 broadside folder
  - Kelley, William V. D. "Adding Color to Motion." Transactions of the Society of Motion Picture Engineers. 3.7 (1919): 76-79. (in Series V), 1919 April (Box 35 (Oversize), Folder 1564)
  - "Key to the Panoramic View of New York." The Illustrated London News. (1876): 181. (in Series V), 1876 August 19 (Box 35 (Oversize), Folder 1565)
  - "Snapshots of Upper Broadway from Thirty-Fourth Street to Central Park." The New York Times-Illustrated Magazine. (1899): 3. (in Series V) (Box 35 (Oversize), Folder 1566)
  - Höffler. "Circa de las Posas, on the Pan de Guajaybon, Cuba." The Illustrated London News. (1869): 393-394. (in Series V), 1869 October 16 (Box 35 (Oversize), Folder 1567)
  - Ward, H. Snowden. "The Work of the Camera." The Sketch. (1894): 687-688. (in Series V), 1894 April 25 (Box 35 (Oversize), Folder 1568)
  - Facsimile reproduction of The Californian newspaper, March 15, 1848 (in Series VI), circa 1970 (Box 35 (Oversize), Folder 1569)
  - Todd, Suzanne. Hawley Family and Interrelated Families of Washington Township (in Series VI), 1993 (Box 36 (Broadside oversize))
  - Lantern slides advertising (in Series VI), 1890-1895 (Box 35 (Oversize), Folder 1570)
  - Moving pictures (in Series VI), 1923-1925 (Box 35 (Oversize), Folder 1571-1574)
  - Photography equipment advertisements, oversize (in Series VI), 1847-1890 (Box 35 (Oversize), Folder 1575-1576)